Wesley C. Haraldson Papers
Wesley C. Haraldson Papers
1966-1967
Haraldson, Wesley C.
0.5 linear ft.
Audiorecordings, memorabilia, speeches/remarks, all relating to Haraldson's work as director of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID).
2741965
Biographical History
Wesley C. Haraldson (1909 or 1910-1996) graduated from Jamestown College in 1935. An economist by training, Haraldson worked first for the Federal Reserve but spent most of his career as a Foreign Service Officer, including work with Taiwan, China, Vietnam, and the Philippines, and served as director of the Agency for International Development (USAID).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Wesley C. Haraldson Papers consist of audiorecordings, memorabilia, and speeches/remarks.
Audiorecordings includes interviews, speeches, and coverage of one of Haraldson's reports.
Memorabilia contains photographs, clippings, a c.v., and a few items of printed material. Some of this material was acquired separately; see Acquisition Information below for details.
Speeches/remarks by Haraldson includes commencement addresses, conference addresses, and a statement given to the House Foreign Affairs Committee.
Arrangement of the Collection
Audiorecordings and speeches/remarks are arranged in chronological order. Memorabilia is in alphabetical order by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Haraldson, Wesley C.; United States. -- Agency for International Development.; USAID/Philippines.; USOM to the Philippines.; Community development -- Philippines.; Economic development -- Philippines.; Rural development -- Philippines.; Philippines -- Politics and government.; Philippines. -- Presidential Arm on Community Development.; Philippines -- Rural conditions.; Sound recordings.; Clippings (information artifacts); Interviews.; Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to audiorecordings requires advance notice to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
Bulk of material, gift of Wesley C. Haraldson, 1967.
Items in Memorabilia: Miscellaneous folder were acquired separately in 2014. They were among some of Mrs. Ada Haraldson's papers that were given to a genealogical society in Phoenix, Arizona, and later transferred to.
Inventory
- Audiorecordings
  - Mr. Wesley Haraldson 10th Anniversary of the Presidential Arm on Community Development P.A.C.D., 1965; haraldson_w_001; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1)
  - [Haraldson at opening ceremonies; awards ceremony], 19 Oct 1966; 3 Apr 1967; haraldson_w_002; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1)
    1. Mr. Haraldson at the opening ceremonies of first in-service training course for Facoma [?] managers April 3, 1967 / 2. Mr. Haraldson receives award for international understanding from Manila Kiwanis Club Oct 19, 1966
  - [Report on Haraldson’s speech; press interview of Haraldson], 11 May 1967; undated; haraldson_w_003; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1)
    1. A report on Mr. Wesley Haraldson’s speech before the Kiwanis Club of Manila / 2. Press interview of Mr. Wesley Haraldson on his “Corruption of R. P. Officials,” a statement made at a U.S. Congress inquiry May 11, 1967
  - Mr. Wesley Haraldson at the 2nd FOA Fellow Conference, Aug. 9. 1967; haraldson_w_004; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Biographical material, photograph, curriculum vitae (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    This folder of material was acquired separately; see Acquisition Information above for details.
- Speeches and remarks
  - First National Conference of Technical Assistance Participants, Manila, 11-13 Aug, 1965 (Box 1)
  - University of the Philippines, 9 Sep 1965 (Box 1)
  - National Science and Technology Week, 6 Dec 1965 (Box 1)
  - Let's Talk Business (television show), 7 Jan 1966 (Box 1)
  - USAID Textbook Project, 5 Apr 1966; on occasion of 20 millionth textbook (Box 1)
  - Commencement exercises, May 1966; Xavier University; Mindanao Institute of Technology (Box 1)
  - Regional Seminar on Public Administration, Davao City, 12 May 1966 (Box 1)
  - United States Congress Committee on Foreign Affairs, Apr 1967 (Box 1)
  - 2nd National Conference, Philippine FAO Fellows, 9 Aug 1967; "Must the Philippines Go Hungry?" (Box 1)